Guide to the Ronald Shiffman collection on the Pratt Center for Community Development 2013.023
Brooklyn Historical Society
Ronald Shiffman collection on the Pratt Center for Community Development
1950-2018
1980-2010
Brooklyn Historical Society
Shiffman, Ron
2013.023
74.37 Linear Feet in 116 manuscript boxes and 26 record cartons.
Ron Shiffman is a city planner, architect, and expert in community economic development and sustainable development assistance for community-based groups in low- and moderate-income neighborhoods. In 1964, Ron Shiffman co-founded the Pratt Institute Center for Community and Environmental Development (known today as the Pratt Center for Community Development). The following year, Shiffman, in partnership with the Central Brooklyn Coordinating Council and Senator Robert F. Kennedy, assisted in the conception and launch of the Bedford Stuyvesant Restoration Corporation, the country's first community development corporation. Shiffman served on the New York City Planning Commission from 1990-1996 and was the Pratt Center's Director until 2003. As of 2018, Shiffman was a Professor Emeritus at Pratt Institute's School of Architecture. This collection documents the broad scope of Shiffman's career from the 1960s to the present, and is a rich source of material pertaining to community-based planning, participatory and advocacy planning, self-help and sweat equity, housing programs and policies, community development corporations, and land use across New York City and internationally.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ronald Shiffman made an initial donation of materials in 2013, with a subsequent donation in 2018.
Conditions Governing Access
The majority of this collection is open to research. Audiovisual material in this collection is not currently avaialble to researchers.
Appraisal
The donor thoroughly reviewed the collection, with guidance from the archivist, in advnace of the transfer of materials to the Brooklyn Historical Society. The archivist removed duplicate materials and commerical broadcasts from the collection.
Related Materials
Arnie Goldwag Brooklyn Congress of Racial Equality (CORE) collection (ARC.002)
Back to the City collection (1991.036)
Bedford Stuyvesant Restoration Corporation Oral History collection (2008.030)
Bedford Stuyvesant Restoration Corporation publication and photograph collection (ARC.124)
Bedford-Stuyvesant Restoration Corporation publication and photograph collection, 1968–2007 (ARC.124)
Bob Adelman photographs of Brooklyn Congress of Racial Equality (CORE) demonstrations (V1989.022)
Brooklyn Chamber of Commerce publications (ARC.165)
Brooklyn neighborhood associations and civic organizations publications (ARC.167)
Downtown Brooklyn Development Association records (1979.021)
Eastern Parkway Coalition records (2007.016)
Everett and Evelyn Ortner papers and photographs (ARC.306)
H. Dickson McKenna collection (ARC.060)
Robert Vadheim Brooklyn Heights Association collection (1988.051)
Robert Vadheim Brooklyn neighborhood renewal and development collection (1987.002)
Sarita Daftary-Steel collection of East New York oral histories (2015.011)
Voices of Brooklyn oral histories: Civic leaders (2008.031)
Additional material of interest includes:
Atlantic Yards/Pacific Park Report
The Brooklyn Paper (Brooklyn, N.Y.), 1978-Present
The Pheonix paper (Brooklyn, N.Y.), 1972-1998
Biographical / Historical
Ronald Shiffman was born in 1938 in Israel. His parents had immigrated to Israel from Russia after his father was imprisoned and exiled to Siberia for expressing Zionist political views. Shiffman's parents later emigrated to the Bronx borough of New York City, where Shiffman grew up. Shiffman graduated from Pratt Institute's School of Architecture, and later its graduate program in City and Regional Planning. In 1964, Shiffman co-founded the Pratt Institute Center for Community and Environmental Development (now known as the Pratt Center for Community Development). The Pratt Center is now the nation's largest public interest architectural, planning, and development office, and is the oldest continuously-operated university-based planning technical assistance and training organization in the United States working with community-based groups in low and moderate-income communities. Shiffman served as the Pratt Center's Director until 2003. Shiffman is now a Professor Emeritus at Pratt Institute's School of Architecture, where he chaired the Department of City and Regional Planning (now known as the Program for Sustainable Planning and Development) from 1991 to 1999.
In 1965, Shiffman assisted the Central Brooklyn Coordinating Council and Senator Robert F. Kennedy to conceive and launch the first community development corporation, known today as the Bedford Stuyvesant Restoration Corporation. Shiffman was appointed to the New York City Planning Commission by Mayor David Dinkins and served on the Planning Commission from 1990-1996. He has also served as a consultant to the Department of Housing and Urban Development, the United States Agency for International Development, and the Ford Foundation on national and global community-based planning, design, and development initiatives. After the fall of apartheid, he was a founding board member of Shared Interest, an organization that guarantees micro-loans for black entrepreneurial economic development enterprises in South Africa. He also served as President of the Salzburg Congress on Urban Planning and Development from 1996-2000, an international organization of architects, planners, and development practitioners. Shiffman was a founding member of the racial justice non-profit the Center for Social Inclusion, which later merged with Race Forward. As of 2018, Shiffman continues to serve on the board of the expanded Race Forward. In 2012, Shiffman was awarded the Jane Jacobs medal for Lifetime Achievement from the Rockefeller Foundation, and the following year he won the Planning Pioneer Award from the American Planning Association.
Scope and Contents
This collection is a rich source of material pertaining to community planning, housing programs and policies, community development corporations, and land use across New York City and internationally. The collection includes a wealth of material about Brooklyn neighborhoods such as Bedford-Stuyvesant, Greenpoint, Williamsburg, the Atlantic Yards and Red Hook. Manhattan locations include Lower Manhattan, Chinatown and Harlem. The collection includes information about a wide variety of housing programs and policies throughout New York City, including mutual housing and land trusts, low-income home ownership and rehabilitation programs, rent regulation, and housing preservation. There is extensive information about the Strycker's Bay, Cooper Square, and Midwood Friends land trusts and mutual housing programs. The collection also includes information about self-help housing efforts in the Lower East Side and the South Bronx.
The initial establishment and development of the community development corporation (CDC) model is well documented in this collection, with a particular focus on the Bedford-Stuyvesant Community Development Corporation. Additional community development projects and organizations throughout the city are also represented. This collection also includes the project files, interviews, and transcripts from Building Hope: The Community Development Corporation Oral History Project. This was a major, Ford Foundation funded project to document the development of the first nineteen CDCs established across the United States.
Shiffman and the Pratt Center's international and environmental involvement is represented through files on affordable housing and community development in South Africa, collaborations with colleagues in Germany on brownfields, and exchanges in France. There is a small series of material pertaining to Shiffman's tenure on the NYC City Planning Commission, as well as on the Pratt Center's Community Economic Development Internship, a training and capacity-building program. The collection also includes a substantial number of publications from the Pratt Center, affiliated organizations, and foundations. These publications represent a wide range of topics similar to those found in the rest of the collection: housing, community-based planning, advocacy and participatory planning, urban renewal and revitalization, urban poverty and community development.
Architects |z New York (State) |z New York; City planning |z New York (State) |z New York; Community development corporations |z New York (State) |z New York; Community organizing |z New York (State) |z New York; Gentrification |z New York (State) |z New York; Gentrification; New York (N.Y.) |x Politics and government; Housing, Cooperative |z New York (State) |z New York; Public housing |z New York (State) |z New York; Low-income housing |z New York (State) |z New York; Urban renewal |z New York (State) |z New York; Bedford-Stuyvesant (New York, N.Y.); South Africa; Germany; Times Square (New York, N.Y.); Greenpoint (New York, N.Y.); Fort Greene (New York, N.Y.); Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Buildings, structures, etc.; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x History; Lower East Side (New York, N.Y.); Lower Manhattan -- New York (N.Y.); Williamsburg (New York, N.Y.); East New York (New York, N.Y.); Coney Island (New York, N.Y.); Crown Heights (New York, N.Y.); Gowanus Canal (New York, N.Y.); Red Hook (New York, N.Y.); Chinatown (New York, N.Y.); Midwood (New York, N.Y.); September 11 Terrorist Attacks, 2001; Zoning -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Affordable housing; Homeslessness -- New York (N.Y.); Housing, Cooperative -- New York (N.Y.); Land trusts -- New York (N.Y.); Brownfields; Community development, Urban |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Urban homesteading; Shiffman, Ron; Bedford-Stuyvesant Restoration Corporation; ACORN; Flatbush Development Corporation (New York, N.Y.); Pratt Center for Community Development; Ford Foundation; New York City Housing Authority; Midwood Friends; United Tenants Association; Urban Homesteading Assistance Board (New York, N.Y.); New York (N.Y.). City Planning Commission
- Series 1: Community Planning Projects
  Scope and Contents
  This series documents Shiffman and the Pratt Center's involvement in community planning for and in opposition to major redevelopment projects throughout New York City, primarily from the mid-1980s through the 2010s. This series includes a substantial amount of materials pertaining to the redevelopment of Lower Manhattan and Chinatown after September 11th, as well as the redevelopment of the Greenpoint and Williamsburg waterfronts through a 197a plan. Other redevelopment projects included in this series are Red Hook, the Gowanus Canal, the Atlantic Yards, and the Columbia University expansion. There are also some materials pertaining to the rebuilding of Coney Island following Hurricane Sandy. Materials in this series include strategic plans, outreach materials, meeting notes and correspondence, planning documents, evaluation forms and others.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged alphabetically by topic.
  - 197a Plan for the Revitalization of Bronx Community District #3, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 42nd Street Light Rail Boulevard, 1995-2000 (Box 110, Folder 1)
  - 9/11 AIA New York New Visions (American Institute of Architects), 2001-2002 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - 9/11 An Info Net for Lower Manhattan -- GCPE Summer 2002 Studio (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 9/11 Civic Alliance -- Listening to the City, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 9/11 Civic Alliance -- Listening to the City II, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 9/11 Civic Alliance -- RPA Regional Plan Association, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
  - 9/11 Empire State Transportation Alliance, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 9/11 Evaluation Forms 1 7/20/02 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 9/11 Evaluation Forms 2 7/20/02 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 9/11 Evaluation Forms 3 7/20/02 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 9/11 Evaluation Forms 4 7/20/02 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 9/11 Evaluation Forms 5 7/20/02 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 9/11 Evaluation Forms 6 7/20/02 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 9/11 Evaluation Forms 7 7/20/02 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 9/11 Evaluation Forms 7/22/02, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - 9/11 Evaluation Forms Foreign Language, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 9/11 Jobs with Justice -- Good Jobs New York, 2001-2003 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - 9/11 Labor Community Advocacy Network (LCAN), 2001-2003 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - 9/11 Libeskind, Daniel, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - 9/11 MAS -- Imagine New York, 2001-2003 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - 9/11 Mayor Bloomberg, 2002-2003 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - 9/11 Memorial, 2000-2002 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - 9/11 Miscellaneous, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - 9/11 New York 2050, 2002-2003 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - 9/11 New York Immigration Coalition, 2001-2002 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - 9/11 News Clippings, 1980-2003 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - 9/11 PICCED, 2001-2002 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - 9/11 Raw Data From Tables 7/20-7/22, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 3-5)
  - 9/11 Recovery, 2001-2002 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 9/11 Ron's Emails, 2001-2002 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - 9/11 University Settlement / Rebuild Coalition / Helen Lee, 2001-2002 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - 9/11 Weblab Online Dialog, 1999-2002 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - 9/11 Women's City Club of New York, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - A Benefit-Cost Analysis of the Bedford-Stuyvesant Restoration Corporation, 1968-1977 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - A Chance to Dream -- Rebuilding Lower Manhattan, undated (Box 142, Item 449)
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    VHS. Runtime: 1:30:00
  - A Chance to Dream: Rebuilding Lower Manhattan, 2002 (Box 143, Item 398)
    VHS. Runtime: 1:00:00
  - A Community-Based Development Strategy for South Africa, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - A Community-Based Development Strategy for South Africa, 1990-1995 (Box 108, Folder 1)
  - A Survey of Industrial Planning in Steinway, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - ACORN Rebuilding After Hurricane Katrina, 2006 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - American Planning Association Annual Awards Program, 1999 (Box 143, Item 401)
    VHS. Runtime: 0:30:00
  - Areas of Strength/Areas of Opportunity - South Bronx Development Office, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Astoria/Steinway, 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Atlantic Yards, 1984-2007 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Atlantic Yards, 2006 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Atlantic Yards, Ratner Unity Plan, 1984-2007 (Box 5, Folder 9-12)
  - Bedford-Stuyvesant Restoration Plaza New York Times Article 2000, 1997-2000 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Brian Sullivan's Center, 1985-1986 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Bridges, Greenpoint/Williamsburg Waterfront Plan, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Bronx, 2005-2007 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Bronx Center Planning, 1992-1994 (Box 6, Folder 6-7)
  - Bronx Court Complex Proposal, 1995-1998 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Bronx Melrose Commons, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Brooklyn Borough President Planning RFP, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Brooklyn Bridge Park Coalition, 1999-2000 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Brooklyn Community District 1, 1990-1998 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Brooklyn Coordinating Council, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Brooklyn Photographs, 1970-2000 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Brooklyn Sports II -- PICCED Stadium Impact Study for New York State Urban Coalition, 1986-1991 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Brooklyn's Renaissance -- The Community Housing Movement, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Camden Master Plan, Community Outreach Plan, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Center for Alternative Sentencing and Employment Opportunities Criminal Justice Project, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Center for Community Change, 1981-1996 (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
  - Central Brooklyn Model Cities Plan, 1969 (Box 110, Folder 9-10)
  - Central Brooklyn Model Cities Plan, 1969 (Box 111, Folder 1-2)
  - Chinatown Association, 2000-2001 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Civic Alliance Meetings, 2001-2002 (Box 7, Folder 4-6)
  - Civic Alliance Meetings, 2001-2002 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Civic Alliance Planning and Design Workshop, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Civic Alliance Rebuild After 911, 2002-2003 (Box 8, Folder 3-5)
  - Civic Alliance, LCAN, RDOT, Imagine New York, PICCED. Post 911 Listening to the City 1, 2001-2003 (Box 7, Folder 7-9)
  - Civil Planning and Sustainable Development, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Columbia University1987 Planning Studio Williamsburg/Greenpoint (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Community Board 9 Manhattan, 2005-2007 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Community Board 9 Manhattan 197a Plan, 2004 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Community Consulting Services Reports, 1999-2001 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Community Design Centers Article, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Community District 9 197a Plan Columbia University, 2005-2007 (Box 9, Folder 5-7)
  - Community District 9 197a Plan Columbia University, 2005-2007 (Box 10, Folder 1-7)
  - Community Planning Handbook Shiffman, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Community Viability Focus Group Meeting, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Community Viability Working Group, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Compliments of Greenpoint Video Project, undated (Box 143, Item 378)
    VHS. Runtime: 2:00:00
  - Comprehensive and Integrative Planning for Community Development, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Comprehensive and Integrative Planning Shiffman/Motley, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Comprehensive Manhattan Waterfront Plan, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Coney Island Recovery, Adaptation, Mitigation, and Planning (RAMP), 2013-2018 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Coney Island Sustainable Communities Studio, 2013 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Conference on Neighborhood Conservation, undated (Box 142, Item 426)
    .25" Helical Scan Video. Runtime: 0:30:00
  - Crown Heights, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - CUNY Forum -- Redeveloping Ground Zero: What is to be Done?, March 19, 2002 (Box 142, Item 438)
  - Density and Social Justice, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Downtown Brooklyn Conceptual Designs, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - East Midtown Coalition for Sensible Development, 2000-2001 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - East New York, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - East River, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Father Panik Village, Bridgeport Connecticut, 1986-1987 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Fifth Avenue Committee, 1995-2000 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Flatbush Development Corporation (FDC), 1982-1988 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Flatbush Development Corporation 1989, 1989-1991 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Flint Michigan Preliminary Proposal Police/Fire, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Flint Neighborhood Improvement and Preservation Project, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Flushing Bedford, 1999 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Fox Hills, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Fulton Park Development Corporation, 1984 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Gowanus Canal, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Gowanus Canal, 1993-1998 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Gowanus Canal Development Corporation 1989, 1986-1993 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Gowanus Canal Development Corproation, 1986-1987 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Grand Concourse Clippings, 1981-1988 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Greenpoint / Williamsburg 197a Plan and Mobil Oil Spill, 1996-1997 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Greenpoint / Williamsburg Waterfront, 1997-2003 (Box 14, Folder 7-10)
  - Greenpoint / Williamsburg Waterfront, 2003 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Greenpoint 197a, 1997-2001 (Box 12, Folder 9-11)
  - Greenpoint 197a 1/24/99, 1998-1999 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Greenpoint 197a Newspaper, 1998 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Greenpoint 197a Plan, 1999 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Greenpoint 197a Plan, 1998-1999 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Greenpoint and Williamsburg 197a Plans, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Greenpoint Data, 1989-1998 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Greenpoint Historic District Designation Report, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Greenpoint Newspapers, 1993-1998 (Box 13, Folder 5-7)
  - Greenpoint Terminal Market, 1999-2000 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Greenpoint Video Project, 1998-2000 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Greenpoint Video Project, BargeMusic at Fulton Ferry Landing, undated (Box 143, Item 374)
    VHS. Runtime: 0:28:00
  - Greenpoint Video Project, Comprehensive Survey Tape, 1998-1999 (Box 143, Item 404)
  - Greenpoint Video Project, George Trakas on Newtown Creek, Department of Environmental Protection Boat Trip, Waterfront Survey, Panorama of Greenpoint Waterfront from Across the East River, 1999 (Box 143, Item 406)
  - Greenpoint Video Project, NAG Public Hearing at Van Arsdale High School Auditorium, Pier 63 Waterfest; and Interview with Adam Brown President of the Working Waterfront Association, and Two Works in Progress -- Greenpoint's Backyard and Greenpoint's Waterfront Access, 1998-1999 (Box 143, Item 405)
  - Greenpoint Video Project, Pete Seeger at Gantry Plaza, undated (Box 143, Item 376)
  - Greenpoint Video Project, Revealing the Edges: Communities and Infrastructure Along the Waterfront, with the Metropolitan Waterfront Alliance Community Design Team, undated (Box 143, Item 377)
  - Greenpoint Waterfront, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Greenpoint Williamsburg Compared with Lessons Shared, 1998 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Greenpoint Zoning, 1979 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - GWAPP, undated (Box 143, Item 383)
  - Herbert Von King Park Neighborhood Study, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Housing Quality -- Melrose Issues, 1994 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Hunters Point Community Coalition, 1995-1999 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Hunters Point, Long Island City: A Neighborhood in Transition; Restoring Vision -- An Exhibit at Pratt, undated (Box 138, Item 299)
  - Imagine New York and Rebuilding After 9/11, 2002-2003 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Implementation of a Sound Urban Renewal Program, 1964 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Konheim and Ketcham -- Big Box, 1995-1997 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Konheim and Ketcham -- Miscellaneous, 1995-1998 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Lessons in Community-Based Planning: The Case of Red Hook, 1996-1999 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Listening to the City, 2002 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Livingston Corridor Plan, 1998 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Long Island City Rezoning, 2001 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Lower Density Zoning, 1989-1990 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Lower East Side, 1981-1983 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Lower Manhattan, 2001-2002 (Box 15, Folder 12-13)
  - Lower Manhattan, 2001 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Manhattan's Waterfront Map, 1996 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - McCarren Park Pool Architects Report, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Mega-Cities, 1995 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Milbank Franley, 1982-1983 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Model Cities Application, 1967 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Myrtle Avenue Coalition, 1979-1980 (Box 16, Folder 7-8)
  - National Congress of Neighborhood Women, 2018 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Neighborhood Preservation in New York City Comprehensive Planning Workshop, 1973 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - New York 2050, Predates Bloomberg Effort, 2003-2004 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Northside Correspondence, 1973-1976 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Old Brooklyn District, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - PICCED Role in the Rebuilding of New York City, 2001 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Planning Progress 1961 City Planning Commission (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Port Morris Bronx, 1997 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Post 9/11 LCAN Civic Alliance, 2003 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Pratt -- MILA Photographs, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Pratt Area Community Council Fort Greene, 1981-1989 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Pratt Center Planning and Community Development, 1980-1995 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Pratt Center Planning and Community Development -- Advocacy Planning at Pratt, 1993 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Pratt Center Planning and Community Development -- Brochure Project, 1980 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Pratt Institute Center for Community Development -- A Chance to Dream: Rebuilding Lower Manhattan, 2003 (Box 142, Item 450)
    VHS NTSC SUBMASTER 525/60. Runtime: 0:54:13
  - Pratt Summer Planning Studio 1996 Greenpoint Waterfront (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Prospect Lefferts Gardens Neighborhood Association (PLGNA ), 1982-1983 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Rebuild Chinatown, 2002-2003 (Box 17, Folder 8)